Michael Titcomb

(415) 385-6173 - michaeldtitcomb@gmail.com

1084 24th st apt. 1

Oakland, Ca 94607

OVERVIEW

I am adaptable, curious and have a knack for interpreting complex technical material to diverse audiences. This has lead to a successful seven-year career in 1-on-1 education. I'm currently interested in pursuing a technical support role as a next step to better accommodate a growing family.

CERTIFICATIONS

Google IT Professional Certificate: Coursera 5/19/19

KEY SKILLS

Communitation

- successfully deliver material to a very wide group of students. I've reached across langage age and culture barriers
- work as a liason between students and parents, teachers and other stakeholders
- explain technical material to diverse audiences

Technical

- o Owns, and maintains Windows, Linux, and MacOS machines
- Builds computers, and repairs salvaged equipment, including componant audio systems and headphones
- Built installed and maintains home network infrastructure
- Extensive home and business use of G-suite, Squarespace, Wordpress and other cloud solutions

Programming

- Python: Basic understanding of tasks relevant to Database Administration (Lists, Tuples, Functions, Classes, NumPy etc.)
- C: Basic, general understanding of key functions (declaring variables, writing to file, loops, functions etc.)
- BASH:Intermediate, including regular use, and comfort with using command line and writing and running simple scripts.

EDUCATION

University of California: Santa Cruz 2010 – 2012

Bachelors in Arts: Philosophy (Cum Laude)

- Recognized with Dean's Honors in 4 of 6 quarters
- GPA of 3.68
- Awarded paid fellowship as "Undergraduate Tutor" -2011
- Accepted into several invitation-only classes

Peralta College Ti

Transfer Credit and Self-Enrichment

District 2006 – 2015

- Completed two semesters of Anatomy and Physiology with cadaver lab
- Completed a statistics class that covered analysis of variance, data visualization, measures of central tendency, probability, and sampling methods
- Worked closely with professors to help lower performing students grasp material through study groups and taking a leadership role in class discussions and group projects

WORK EXPERIENCE

Brandon College 2019-present

SAT and Precalculus instructor

- Works with a diverse student population, consisting of Emglish Language Learners
- Designed and implemented curricula to efficiently deliver the most essential test taking strategies utilizing Google Docs, Google Sheets, Google Slides and many online teaching resources
- Provides 1-on-1 academic support to high school students in all subjects, as well as general support with executive function
- Tracks student success with regular drills and excercizes

Lindamood Learning Processes 2016 – 2018

Lindamood-Bell Clinician and Mentor

- Provided 1-on-1 instruction and support to students experiencing challenges with literacy, comprehension, and verbal communication
- Engaged with a diverse student population
- Implemented several sensory-cognitive focused programs including the Seeing Stars, Visualizing and Verbalizing, and Talkies Programs
- Implemented high-school level mathematics curricula through Lindamood-Bell Academy
- Modified curricula to differentiate instruction according to student aptitudes, challenges, and goals
- Successfully taught student with diverse learning differences including: Autism Spectrum Disorders, Prader-Willi Syndrome, Dyslexia, Dysgraphia, Attention Deficit Disorder and Spoken Language Disorders
- Built effective working relationships with children at every developmental level, many of whom needed special attention to specific phobias, aversions, and compulsions
- Non-judgmentally steered clients toward pro-social interaction with peers and staff
- Was promoted to a mentor, evaluating educators and sharing tips for engaging and working with students

TutorCorps, Varsity Tutors and Private Commissions 2013 - present

Tutor

- Teaches high-school mathematics including: algebra 1, geometry, alegbra 2 & pre-calculus
- Teaches effective composition through the graduate school level
- Plans lessons tailored to student goals and needs
- Effectively manages scheduling, billing, and client contact
- Coordinates online tutoring sessions using Skype, FaceTime, and Google Hangouts

Mobile Minds Tutoring and Club Z Tutoring 2012 – 2013

SES Tutor

- Taught elementary and middle school mathematics including prealgebra, arithmetic and word problems
- Taught fundamental literacy skills to English Language Learners
- Tracked student success by administering diagnostic, benchmark, and exit standardized tests
- Consulted with parents to tailor my instruction to student needs, often across a language barrier

HOBBIES

I enjoy hands on, productive passtimes like watch repair, refinishing furniture, and maintenance of computers hardware, software and peripharals.